const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following key enzymes is required for the synthesis of acetylcholine?","answers":[{"option":"Choline acetyltransferase","bool":true},{"option":"Choline acetylsynthetase","bool":false},{"option":"Choline synthetase","bool":false},{"option":"Choline acyltransferase","bool":false},{"option":"Acetyl cholineaminase","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following veins is not a tributary of the cavernous sinus?","answers":[{"option":"Straight sinus","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior ophthalmic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Central vein of retina","bool":false},{"option":"Superior ophthalmic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenoparietal sinus","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following veins drains into the superior sagittal sinus?","answers":[{"option":"Deep middle cerebral veins","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial middle cerebral veins","bool":false},{"option":"Striate veins","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cerebral veins","bool":false},{"option":"Superior cerebral veins","bool":true}]},{"id":3,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following cranial nerves does not originate at the pontomedullary junction of the brainstem?","answers":[{"option":"Olfactory nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibulocochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Nervus intermedius","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following arteries is not a part of the circle of Willis?","answers":[{"option":"Middle cerebral artery","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior communicating artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior communicating artery","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following statements regarding the long association fibers is incorrect?","answers":[{"option":"Lie deep beneath the cerebral cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Superior longitudinal fasciculus is the largest bundle of nerve fibers","bool":false},{"option":"They connect adjacent gyri","bool":true},{"option":"The cingulum is an example of long association fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Composed of white matter","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 44-year-old patient presents to the outpatient clinic with the complaint of being unable to recall any recently occurring events. Which of the following brain structures is responsible for converting short-term memory into long-term memory?","answers":[{"option":"Indusium griseum","bool":false},{"option":"Fornix","bool":false},{"option":"Hippocampus","bool":true},{"option":"Parahippocampal gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Prefrontal cortex","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 67-year-old male patient admitted to the neurology ward is observed to have intention tremor and cerebellar ataxia. Radiological scans reveal a pontine infarct. Which of the following fibers is most likely damaged in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Corticopontocerebellar tract","bool":true},{"option":"Parasympathetic fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Auditory fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Sympathetic fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Corticospinal tract","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following is not a feature of postganglionic neurons of the sympathetic nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Are short in length","bool":true},{"option":"The cell bodies of postganglionic neurons are in autonomic ganglia located peripherally","bool":false},{"option":"Originate away from the effector organs","bool":false},{"option":"Noradrenergic","bool":false},{"option":"Unmyelinated","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 62-year-old male patient is diagnosed with early-stage Parkinson's disease. The neurological examination reveals a slight resting tremor of the left hand, slow gait, and lack of the normal range of facial expression. Which of the following is the most likely site of the degenerative changes at this stage of the patient's disease?","answers":[{"option":"Right substantia niagra","bool":true},{"option":"Right globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Bilateral substantia niagra","bool":false},{"option":"Left globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Left substantia niagra","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following structures forms the anterior boundary of the interventricular foramen of Monro?","answers":[{"option":"Crura of fornix","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior column of fornix","bool":false},{"option":"Body of fornix","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior column of fornix","bool":true},{"option":"Fimbria of fornix","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 50-year-old male patient undergoes a CT scan which reveals a tumor of the midbrain. It shows symmetrical distension of the lateral ventricles and the third ventricle. Which of the following structures is most likely obstructed by the tumor in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Central canal","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral aqueduct","bool":true},{"option":"Foramen of Magendie","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen of Monroe","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen of Luschka","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 53-year-old patient was brought to the emergency department after a fall. MRI scan reveals a slipped disc at the L3 level. Neurological examination shows that the patient has a bilateral loss of pain, temperature, and light touch sensation below the level of the lesion, bilateral lower motor neuron paralysis in the segment of the lesion, and bilateral spastic paralysis below the level of the lesion. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Syringomyelia","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cord syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Brown-SÃ©quard syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Central cord syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Complete cord transection syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"The sensation of discriminative touch, vibratory sense, and conscious muscle joint proprioception of the lower limbs passes from the posterior root ganglia to the postcentral gyrus through which of the following pathways?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic and spinal lemniscus pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic and spinal lemniscus pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Fasciculus gracilis and spinal lemniscus pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic and medial lemniscus pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Fasciculus gracilis and medial lemniscus pathway","bool":true}]},{"id":14,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following embryological structures gives rise to the dorsal sensory horn of the spinal cord?","answers":[{"option":"Roof plate","bool":false},{"option":"Alar plate","bool":true},{"option":"Floor plate","bool":false},{"option":"Marginal layer","bool":false},{"option":"Basal plate","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A parasympathetic nerve arising from the brainstem influences the lungs. The cell body of this nerve lies in which of the following nuclei?","answers":[{"option":"Dorsal nucleus of vagus","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior salivatory nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior salivatory nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimatory nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Edinger-Westphal nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 24-year-old patient presents to the emergency department after a road accident with complaints of headache, nausea, vomiting & an altered level of consciousness. An X-ray of the skull reveals a fracture of the cribriform plate of the ethmoid bone. Which of the following cranial nerves passes through the foramina of this fractured bone?","answers":[{"option":"CN IV","bool":false},{"option":"CN V","bool":false},{"option":"CN II","bool":false},{"option":"CN III","bool":false},{"option":"CN I","bool":true}]},{"id":17,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"During a routine examination of a newborn baby in the pediatric clinic, the physician notices a depression of the anterior fontanelle (membranous gap in between bones of the skull). The depressed fontanelle lies between which of the following bones?","answers":[{"option":"Parietal and temporal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal and petrous part of temporal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal and mastoid part of temporal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal and parietal bone","bool":true},{"option":"Parietal and occipital bone","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A patient who suffered from a road traffic accident is brought to the emergency room with a skull fracture involving bones of the anterior cranial fossa. Which of the following skull bones is most likely to be fractured in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Clivius","bool":false},{"option":"Lesser wings of sphenoid","bool":true},{"option":"Parietal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Greater wings of sphenoid","bool":false},{"option":"Temporal bone","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A diabetic patient is observed to have mydriasis while undergoing an examination in an ophthalmology clinic. All other eye movements are normal. The nerve most likely affected in this case arises from which of the following brain stem nuclei?","answers":[{"option":"Superior salivatory nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus Ambiguus","bool":false},{"option":"Motor nucleus of CN III","bool":false},{"option":"Edinger-Westphal nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Spinal nucleus of CN V","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A neonate is diagnosed with obstructive hydrocephalus. The parents were counseled and told that this condition is due to the blockage of a conduit between two ventricles of the brain. Which of the following is the most likely conduit obstructed in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Foramen of Monro","bool":false},{"option":"Paired foramen of Luschka","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen of Magendie","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen of Luschka","bool":false},{"option":"Aqueduct of Sylvius","bool":true}]},{"id":21,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"An unconscious male patient is brought to the emergency room. An MRI of the brain is performed and reveals infarction of the medial surface of the cerebral hemispheres. Which of the following cortical areas is likely to be affected in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Superior parietal lobule","bool":false},{"option":"Superior temporal gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Middle frontal gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior frontal gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Paracentral lobule","bool":true}]},{"id":22,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A patient suffers from a gunshot wound injuring his spinal cord on the left side. The patient now has loss of pain and temperature sensation on the right side of the body. Which of the following tracts is likely to be affected in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Left anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Left lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":true},{"option":"Dorsal column medial lemniscus pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Right lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Right anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A cross-section of the cerebellum shows the cerebellar nuclei embedded in the white matter which is surrounded by the cortex. Which of the following nuclei is located most medially?","answers":[{"option":"Emboliform","bool":false},{"option":"Globose","bool":false},{"option":"Dentate","bool":false},{"option":"Putamen","bool":false},{"option":"Fastigial","bool":true}]},{"id":24,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"During a lecture on the basal nuclei, the professor mentions a part of the corpus striatum which is associated with the lateral ventricle medially and the internal capsule laterally. Which of the following structures of the corpus striatum is being mentioned?","answers":[{"option":"Caudate nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Claustrum","bool":false},{"option":"Putamen","bool":false},{"option":"Amygdaloid nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"The two parietal bones form the sides and the roof of the skull and articulate with each other in the midline. Which of the following sutures is present between these bones?","answers":[{"option":"Sphenofrontal suture","bool":false},{"option":"Coronal suture","bool":false},{"option":"Lambdoid suture","bool":false},{"option":"Sagittal suture","bool":true},{"option":"Squamous suture","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Within the cerebellar cortex, a basket-like nest is formed around the soma of which of the following cells?","answers":[{"option":"Basket cells","bool":false},{"option":"Stellate cells","bool":false},{"option":"Granule cells","bool":false},{"option":"Pyramidal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Purkinje cells","bool":true}]},{"id":27,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"The cerebellar cortex is composed of three layers. Which of the following layers is a synaptic zone that is mainly composed of dendritic arborizations of Purkinje cells?","answers":[{"option":"Pyramidal cell layer","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Purkinje cell layer","bool":false},{"option":"Granular cell layer","bool":false},{"option":"Molecular layer","bool":true}]},{"id":28,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"During the development of the spinal cord, the central canal is lined by three layers. Which of the three layers contains cell bodies of neurons?","answers":[{"option":"Ependymal layer","bool":false},{"option":"Marginal layer","bool":false},{"option":"Alar plate","bool":false},{"option":"Mantle layer","bool":true},{"option":"Ventricular layer","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"During the 5th week of development, five brain swellings appear. These include the telencephalon, diencephalon, mesencephalon, metencephalon, and myelencephalon. The mesencephalon gives rise to which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebrum","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"The speed of a nerve impulse is independent of which of the following factors?","answers":[{"option":"Diameter of nerve fiber","bool":false},{"option":"Physiological condition of the nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of myelin","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of neurolemmocyte","bool":false},{"option":"Length of nerve fiber","bool":true}]},{"id":31,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 20-year-old male was walking barefoot when he suddenly withdrew his leg when he accidentally stepped on a nail. Which of the following reflexes is responsible for activating the antagonistic contralateral extensor muscles in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Crossed extensor reflex","bool":true},{"option":"Plantar reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Stretch reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Babinski reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Visceral reflex","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"During a study, the response of a particular reflex is inhibited for a while and then released suddenly, resulting in a response that is stronger than normal. This is known as which of the following properties of a reflex?","answers":[{"option":"Central delay","bool":false},{"option":"Rebound phenomenon","bool":true},{"option":"Habituation","bool":false},{"option":"Summation","bool":false},{"option":"Reciprocal innervation","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 55-year-old male presented to the neurology clinic with the complaint of excessive daytime sleepiness. He was advised to undergo a sleep study. Just after midnight, the lab technician notices the EEG wave showing K complexes and sleep spindles. Which of the following stages of sleep is the patient in at that moment?","answers":[{"option":"Stage 3 (N3) of NREM sleep","bool":false},{"option":"Stages 1-3 of NREM sleep","bool":false},{"option":"Stage 4 REM sleep","bool":false},{"option":"Stage 2 (N2) of NREM sleep","bool":true},{"option":"Stage 1 (N1) of NREM sleep","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following neurotransmitters is released by the Raphe neurons nerve endings is associated with the induction of sleep?","answers":[{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"GABA","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":true}]},{"id":35,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following parts of the cerebellum is involved in the planning of sequential movements?","answers":[{"option":"Spinocerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Intermediate zone","bool":false},{"option":"Flocculonodular lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Vermis","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral zone","bool":true}]},{"id":36,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following cerebellar disorders results in an inability to combine the various components of a movement to create a smooth action?","answers":[{"option":"Asynergia","bool":true},{"option":"Ataxia","bool":false},{"option":"Dysmetria","bool":false},{"option":"Asthenia","bool":false},{"option":"Dysdiadochokinesia","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following nuclei of the basal ganglia receives input from the sub-thalamus via the indirect pathway?","answers":[{"option":"Substantia niagra","bool":false},{"option":"Lentiform nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Caudate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Globus pallidus internus","bool":true},{"option":"Putamen","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 66-year-old male patient suffers from a cerebrovascular accident resulting in a complete loss of sensation on the right side of the body sparing the head and face. Which of the following nuclei of the thalamus is most likely to be affected by this lesion?","answers":[{"option":"Ventral anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Ventral posterolateral","bool":true},{"option":"Ventral lateral","bool":false},{"option":"Ventral posteromedial","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral geniculate","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following brain waves are most likely to be present in the EEG of a healthy sleeping person and a brain-damaged awake person?","answers":[{"option":"Alpha waves","bool":false},{"option":"Gamma waves","bool":false},{"option":"Beta waves","bool":false},{"option":"Theta waves","bool":false},{"option":"Delta waves","bool":true}]},{"id":40,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 40-year-old woman suffers from a cut injuring a peripheral nerve. The distance between the two ends of the damaged nerve is less than 3 mm. Which of the following cells is responsible for the regeneration of this nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Oligodendrocyte","bool":false},{"option":"Ependymal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Microglia","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Schwaan cells","bool":true}]},{"id":41,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A neurologist plans to conduct a study on the properties of sensory neurons. Which of the following types of neurons is most appropriate for this study?","answers":[{"option":"Motor neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Bipolar neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Multipolar neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Unipolar neurons","bool":true},{"option":"Interneurons","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 2-year-old boy developed flaccid paralysis after being infected with poliovirus. Poliovirus enters the central nervous system from peripheral nerves and reaches the soma by retrograde transport. Which of the following proteins is used by the virus to reach the cell body?","answers":[{"option":"Kinesin","bool":false},{"option":"Synaptobrevin","bool":false},{"option":"Synaptotagmin","bool":false},{"option":"Syntaxin","bool":false},{"option":"Dynein","bool":true}]},{"id":43,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"In an experimental lab, multiple stimuli from different neurons are applied to a post-synaptic neuron simultaneously to generate an action potential. Which one of the following phenomena of a synapse is displayed here?","answers":[{"option":"Presynaptic inhibition","bool":false},{"option":"Divergence","bool":false},{"option":"Spatial summation","bool":true},{"option":"Convergence","bool":false},{"option":"Temporal summation","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following types of inhibition is mediated by inhibitory interneurons in the spinal cord and tends to produce the effect of lateral inhibition?","answers":[{"option":"Presynaptic inhibition","bool":false},{"option":"Renshaw cell inhibition","bool":true},{"option":"Reciprocal inhibition","bool":false},{"option":"Postsynaptic inhibition","bool":false},{"option":"Indirect inhibition","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 42-year-old jackhammer operator presents in the neurology clinic with decreased sensitivity to high-frequency vibrations in the non-hairy skin of his hands. Which of the following receptors is most likely affected in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Ruffini endings","bool":false},{"option":"Hair sensory fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Pacinian corpuscles","bool":true},{"option":"Merkel discs","bool":false},{"option":"Free nerve endings","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"The brain can distinguish between the strengths of light touch and sustained pressure during sensory encoding. Which of the following properties is responsible for this action of the brain?","answers":[{"option":"Type of stimulus","bool":false},{"option":"Frequency of action potential","bool":false},{"option":"Location of receptor","bool":true},{"option":"Duration of stimulus","bool":false},{"option":"Area of receptive field","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 32-year-old male presents to the emergency department with head trauma after he fell from a ladder. A physician shines a flashlight into the patient's eyes and observes that the pupillary reflexes are normal. This reflex is used to test the functioning of which of the following structures of the brain?","answers":[{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":true},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Motor cortex","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"The lateral lemniscus is part of a pathway carrying which of the following sensations?","answers":[{"option":"Temperature","bool":false},{"option":"Touch","bool":false},{"option":"Auditory","bool":true},{"option":"Pain","bool":false},{"option":"Proprioception","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 72-year-old female patient presents to the outpatient clinic with the complaint of being unable to raise her shoulders and turn her head. Investigations reveal a lesion in the medulla. Which of the following cranial nerves is most likely to be affected by this lesion?","answers":[{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglossal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following functions of the brain is affected when there is damage to the peri-aqueductal gray area of the midbrain?","answers":[{"option":"Arousal and alertness of the cerebral cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Control of respiratory movements","bool":false},{"option":"Coordination of head and neck movements","bool":false},{"option":"Maintenance of postural muscle tone","bool":false},{"option":"Endogenous built-in pain suppression","bool":true}]},{"id":51,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 60-year-old male patient is suspected to be suffering from impairment of the otolith organs based on a detailed neurological examination and a CT scan. Which of the following functions is most likely to be disturbed in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Prediction of disequilibrium of body with a sudden turn","bool":false},{"option":"Elicitation of the vestibulo-ocular reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Rotation of head to one side","bool":false},{"option":"Recognition of angular acceleration of head","bool":false},{"option":"Detection of the position of the head with respect to gravity","bool":true}]},{"id":52,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"In an animal laboratory, the change in the behavior of a monkey is observed. The monkey has a loss of fear, forgetfulness, and the tendency to place everything in its mouth. Ablation of which of the following structures of the limbic system is the most likely cause for these behavioral changes?","answers":[{"option":"Cingulate gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Prefrontal cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Hippocampus","bool":false},{"option":"Amygdala","bool":true}]},{"id":53,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 45-year-old male presented to a neurology clinic with complaints of spontaneous and continuous writhing movement of hands, an arm, and face. MRI scans reveal a lesion of the globus pallidus. The patient is manifesting which of the following signs in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Parkinson's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Nystagmus","bool":false},{"option":"Athetosis","bool":true},{"option":"Chorea","bool":false},{"option":"Hemiballismus","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"The myelin sheath of the neurons is altered due to the formation of plaques in which of the following disorders of the nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Epilepsy","bool":false},{"option":"Parkinson's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral palsy","bool":false},{"option":"Neurosyphilis","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple sclerosis","bool":true}]},{"id":55,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following cranial nerves are a part of the parasympathetic nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"III, V, IX, and X","bool":false},{"option":"III, IV, VII, and IX","bool":false},{"option":"V, IX, X, and XII","bool":false},{"option":"IV, V, IX, and X","bool":false},{"option":"III, VII, IX, and X","bool":true}]},{"id":56,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Before a minor surgical procedure, a local anesthetic is injected by the surgeon to ensure that the patient feels no pain. Which of the following nerve fibers is most likely to be blocked by the local anesthetic?","answers":[{"option":"Type B fibers","bool":false},{"option":"A alpha fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Type C fibers","bool":true},{"option":"A beta fibers","bool":false},{"option":"A gamma fibers","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following substances is released by interneurons in the dorsal horn of the spinal cord to inhibit ascending pain signals?","answers":[{"option":"Serotonin","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamate","bool":false},{"option":"GABA","bool":false},{"option":"Enkephalin","bool":true},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"During voluntary movements, the Golgi tendon organs are involved in providing which of the following information to the central nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Tension developed in the muscle being moved","bool":true},{"option":"Activity of type 1a nerve fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Change in the joint angle produced by movement","bool":false},{"option":"Length of the muscle being moved","bool":false},{"option":"Velocity of movement","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following hormones or factors is responsible for inhibiting the action of leptin on the ventromedial nucleus of the hypothalamus and stimulating the lateral hypothalamic nucleus producing a sense of hunger?","answers":[{"option":"Ghrelin","bool":true},{"option":"Stretch of the Gastrointestinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Î±-MSH","bool":false},{"option":"Leptin","bool":false},{"option":"Insulin","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following mechanisms is involved in the conversion of short-term memory to long-term memory?","answers":[{"option":"Post-tetanic potentiation","bool":false},{"option":"Circuit of reverberating neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Long-term potentiation","bool":true},{"option":"Habituation","bool":false},{"option":"Sensitization","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 45-year-old male patient suffering from a head injury undergoes a neurological examination. The neurologist observes that the patient can understand both spoken and written words but his speech is slow, poorly articulated, and requires significant effort. Which of the following areas of the cerebral cortex is most likely to be damaged in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Arcuate fasciculus","bool":false},{"option":"Somatosensory area","bool":false},{"option":"Angular gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Wernicke's area","bool":false},{"option":"Broca's area","bool":true}]},{"id":62,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"The deficiency of which of the following vitamins is marked by anemia, impaired neurotransmitter production, increased homocysteine levels, and neuronal demyelination?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin B2","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B3","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B6","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B12","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin B1","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following vitamins is required for the synthesis of neurotransmitters like dopamine, serotonin, and GABA?","answers":[{"option":"Thiamine","bool":false},{"option":"Niacin","bool":false},{"option":"Pyridoxine","bool":true},{"option":"Riboflavin","bool":false},{"option":"Cyanocobalamin","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"In the blood-brain barrier, the endothelial cells are tightly packed together by means of tight junctions that are formed by which of the following specialized transmembrane proteins?","answers":[{"option":"Glycophorins","bool":false},{"option":"Claudins","bool":true},{"option":"Integrins","bool":false},{"option":"Selectins","bool":false},{"option":"Rhodopsins","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following compounds crosses the blood-brain barrier by means of receptor-mediated transcytosis?","answers":[{"option":"Leucine","bool":false},{"option":"Free fatty acids","bool":false},{"option":"Insulin","bool":true},{"option":"Glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Phenylalanine","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Parkinson's disease is associated with the loss of specific neurons containing which of the following neurotransmitters?","answers":[{"option":"Dopamine","bool":true},{"option":"GABA","bool":false},{"option":"Indolamines","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A cobweb coagulum is a characteristic finding on CSF examination in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Viral meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Subarachnoid hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Brain tumour","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculous meningitis","bool":true}]},{"id":68,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 39-year-old female patient presents to the outpatient department with a severe headache for the last 3 days. On physical examination, she is afebrile and normotensive. Fundoscopic examination shows papilledema in the right eye. She was admitted to the hospital for further testing. A day later, she develops right pupillary dilation with impaired ocular movement. These findings are best explained by which of the following lesions?","answers":[{"option":"Subdural hematoma","bool":false},{"option":"Transtentorial medial temporal herniation","bool":true},{"option":"Frontal lobe abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Ruptured berry aneurysm","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocephalus","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A female infant born after a full-term pregnancy weighing 3.4kg has an enlarged head with the occipitofrontal circumference (OFC) being 49.5 cm. A cranial ultrasound reveals bilateral ventriculomegaly. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Hydrocephalus","bool":true},{"option":"Herniation","bool":false},{"option":"Encephalitis","bool":false},{"option":"Meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral edema","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 35-year-old male who has a history of HIV is admitted to the neurology ward with signs and symptoms of encephalitis. Which of the following is a characteristic histopathological finding of HIV encephalitis?","answers":[{"option":"Microglial nodules","bool":false},{"option":"Eosinophilia","bool":false},{"option":"Microglial nodules and multinucleated giant cells","bool":true},{"option":"Gliosis","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophil infiltration","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following is not a risk factor for encephalitis?","answers":[{"option":"People with a weak immune system","bool":false},{"option":"People with a strong immune system","bool":true},{"option":"Children under the age of 1 year","bool":false},{"option":"HIV infection","bool":false},{"option":"Older age","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 50-year-old female patient who is a known case of an autoimmune disorder visits the neurology clinic with complaints of fatigue, tingling, numbness, muscle weakness, and muscle spasms. CSF analysis reveals oligoclonal bands. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Multiple sclerosis","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebral edema","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral herniation","bool":false},{"option":"Central pontine myelinolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Subdural hematoma","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 5-month-old boy is brought to the outpatient clinic with complaints of global developmental delay, generalized weakness of the body, and jerky eye movement. There is also a family history of his 5-year-old  brother having the same complaints. MRI scans of the brain reveal symmetrical lesions. Genetic studies reveal a mutation in the ABCD1 gene located at the X chromosome. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Canavan disease","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenoleukodystrophy","bool":true},{"option":"Alexander disease","bool":false},{"option":"Metachromatic leukodystrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple sclerosis","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 5-year-old boy is admitted to the neurology ward with complaints of headache, photophobia, and neck rigidity. He is a suspected case of meningitis. Which of the following is the best diagnostic investigation for meningitis?","answers":[{"option":"CSF analysis","bool":true},{"option":"Urine test","bool":false},{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"MRI brain","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 1-year-old girl is diagnosed with bacterial meningitis. Which of the following findings in the CSF analysis are suggestive of bacterial meningitis?","answers":[{"option":"Increased glucose content in CSF","bool":false},{"option":"100-2000 polymorphs","bool":true},{"option":"No lymphocytes and polymorphs","bool":false},{"option":"Clear CSF","bool":false},{"option":"100-500 lymphocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A young male patient presents to the emergency department in an unconscious state. The parents give a history of him swimming in a pool for the last few days. CSF analysis reveals small flask-shaped amoeba. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Naegleria fowleri","bool":true},{"option":"Acanthamoeba","bool":false},{"option":"Cysticercosis","bool":false},{"option":"Candida albicans","bool":false},{"option":"Prion disease","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 60-year-old male patient with a history of hypertension for the last 10 years is brought to the emergency department in an unconscious state. History also reveals that the patient is non-compliant with his medication for hypertension. MRI and CT scan brain show a lobar hemorrhage. Which of the following is the most likely cause of this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Arteriovenous malformation","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral amyloid angiopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":true}]},{"id":78,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following is an inhibitory neurotransmitter that causes hyperpolarization of neurons?","answers":[{"option":"Glutamate","bool":false},{"option":"GABA (gamma aminobutyric acid)","bool":true},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"The analgesic properties of opioids are primarily mediated by which of the following receptors?","answers":[{"option":"Adrenergic receptor","bool":false},{"option":"Kappa receptor","bool":false},{"option":"Mu receptor","bool":true},{"option":"Delta receptor","bool":false},{"option":"Cholinergic receptor","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 36-year-old man is hired as a laboratory worker and he will be handling Rabies related viruses and vaccines. Which of the following vaccines is he advised to get?","answers":[{"option":"Pre-exposure prophylaxis","bool":true},{"option":"H-RIG (human rabies immunoglobulin)","bool":false},{"option":"Post-exposure prophylaxis","bool":false},{"option":"E-RIG (equine rabies immunoglobulin)","bool":false},{"option":"Tetanus","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 32-year-old mother of two children visits a primary healthcare center with complaints of feeling sad, irritable, and empty, and often finds herself crying for no reason for the past three months. She has a loss of interest in all activities and finds it really hard to carry out her daily activities. She feels as if she would be better off dead and even has thoughts about taking her life at times. Which one of the following disorders is she most likely suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Schizophrenia","bool":false},{"option":"Bipolar disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Post-traumatic stress disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Anxiety","bool":false},{"option":"Depression","bool":true}]},{"id":82,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following terms refers to the constant presence of a disease or infectious agent within its usual or expected frequency in a given geographical area or population group?","answers":[{"option":"Sporadic","bool":false},{"option":"Epidemic","bool":false},{"option":"Incidence","bool":false},{"option":"Prevalence","bool":false},{"option":"Endemic","bool":true}]},{"id":83,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Polic is now endemic in only 2 countries; Pakistan and Afghanistan. Two very effective polio vaccines, the oral and injectable vaccines are being given in the EPI program, and in addition, special immunization campaigns are repeatedly conducted all over Pakistan to eradicate polio. In the routine EPI schedule, which of the following is the correct age for the administration of the injectable polio vaccine (IPV)?","answers":[{"option":"10 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"9 months","bool":false},{"option":"14 weeks and 9 months","bool":true},{"option":"14 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"6 weeks","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"John diverts his attention to stop thinking about disturbing events in order to prevent himself from experiencing any overwhelming negative emotions. Which of the following term best corresponds to this strategy?","answers":[{"option":"Cognitive reappraisal","bool":false},{"option":"Antecedent based strategies","bool":true},{"option":"Response focused strategies","bool":false},{"option":"Situation selection","bool":false},{"option":"Response modulation","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"During a flood, a mental health professional is given the responsibility to provide psychological first aid and conduct crisis intervention. Which of the following is the 7th and last stage of the crisis intervention model?","answers":[{"option":"Develop and formulate an action plan","bool":false},{"option":"Plan and conduct a crisis intervention","bool":false},{"option":"Generate and explore alternatives","bool":false},{"option":"Establish follow-up plan and agreement","bool":true},{"option":"Deal with feelings and emotions","bool":false}]}]
export default arr